[{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d058f0e18f52c3bc199c","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":1,"question":"What is the default port number of HTTP?\n\nA) 21\nB) 25\nC) 80\nD) 443","answer":"C","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d14bf0e18f52c3bc199e","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":2,"question":"What happens if you dereference a NULL pointer?\n\nA) Returns 0\nB) Returns garbage\nC) Runtime error (Segmentation fault)\nD) Compilation error","answer":"C","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d19ff0e18f52c3bc19a0","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":3,"question":"What is pointer arithmetic?\n\nA) Performing arithmetic operations directly on memory addresses as raw byte values\n\nB) Performing arithmetic operations on a pointer where the increment/decrement depends on the size of the data type it points to\n\nC) Adding two pointers to obtain a new valid memory address\n\nD) Changing the value stored at the memory location using arithmetic operators","answer":"B","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d21cf0e18f52c3bc19a2","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":4,"question":"Which traversal of a binary tree uses recursion naturally?\n\nA) Level Order\nB) Breadth First Search\nC) Depth First Search\nD) Hash Traversal","answer":"C","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d256f0e18f52c3bc19a4","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":5,"question":"Which algorithm is used to find the shortest path in a weighted graph with non-negative weights?\n\nA) BFS\nB) Dijkstra’s Algorithm\nC) DFS\nD) Kruskal’s Algorithm","answer":"B","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d28ff0e18f52c3bc19a6","questionType":"MCQ","questionNo":6,"question":"In a complete binary tree with n nodes, the height is approximately:\n\nA) n\nB) log n\nC) n log n\nD) √n","answer":"B","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d67af0e18f52c3bc19b0","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":1,"question":"A connected acyclic graph is called a __________.","answer":"Tree","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d6abf0e18f52c3bc19b2","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":2,"question":"The ACID property “A” stands for __________.","answer":"Atomicity","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d6d4f0e18f52c3bc19b4","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":3,"question":"The memory area used for dynamic allocation is called the __________.","answer":"Heap","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d706f0e18f52c3bc19b6","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":4,"question":"In DBMS, a dependency where a non-prime attribute depends on another non-prime attribute is called __________ dependency.","answer":"Transitive","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d75df0e18f52c3bc19b8","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":5,"question":"The memory used by local variables inside a function is stored in the __________ segment.","answer":"Stack","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d7aef0e18f52c3bc19ba","questionType":"FITB","questionNo":6,"question":"In hashing with chaining, collisions are handled using a __________.","answer":"Linked List","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d905f0e18f52c3bc19bc","questionType":"TC","questionNo":1,"question":"What is the worst-case time complexity of searching in a hash table (with chaining)?\n\nA) O(1)\nB) O(log n)\nC) O(n)\nD) O(n log n)","answer":"C","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d91af0e18f52c3bc19be","questionType":"TC","questionNo":2,"question":"What is the time complexity of inserting an element into a binary heap?\n\nA) O(1)\nB) O(log n)\nC) O(n)\nD) O(n log n)","answer":"B","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d92bf0e18f52c3bc19c0","questionType":"TC","questionNo":3,"question":"What is the time complexity of BFS traversal of a graph?\n\nA) O(V + E)\nB) O(V²)\nC) O(E log V)\nD) O(V log E)","answer":"A","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d958f0e18f52c3bc19c2","questionType":"TC","questionNo":4,"question":"What is the time complexity?\n\nfor(int i = 0; i < n; i++)\n    for(int j = 0; j < i*i; j++)\n        printf(\"%d\", j);\n\nA) O(n²)\nB) O(n³)\nC) O(n log n)\nD) O(n⁴)","answer":"B","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d9b1f0e18f52c3bc19c4","questionType":"TC","questionNo":5,"question":"What is the time complexity?\n\nfor(int i = n; i > 0; i /= 2)\n    for(int j = 0; j < i; j++)\n        printf(\"%d\", j);\n\nA) O(n)\nB) O(n log n)\nC) O(n²)\nD) O(log n)","answer":"A","points":10},{"options":[],"_id":"69a3d9baf0e18f52c3bc19c6","questionType":"TC","questionNo":6,"question":"What is the time complexity?\n\nfor(int i = 0; i < n; i++)\n    for(int j = 0; j < sqrt(n); j++)\n        printf(\"%d\", j);\n\nA) O(n)\nB) O(n√n)\nC) O(n²)\nD) O(√n)","answer":"B","points":10}]